# Mohsin Khan

DoB: Oct. 26, 1991; Married; Hong Kong PR Holder

I want to work on challenging tasks in a favourable working environment where I can utilize my knowledge, skills and experience in game programming efficiently.

### Sai Ying Pun, Hong Kong Island, Hong Kong

© (852) 9478 0874

M<sup>Gmail</sup> mohsinkhan.se

mohsinkhan26.github.io

mohsinkhan26

O /mohsinkhan26

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Hong Kong Shue Yan University,** Hong Kong — *Game Developer*

May 2023 - Till now

Working on an Educational farm base building game from scratch with its Firebase backend

## **The University of Hong Kong**, Hong Kong — *Game Developer*

November 2017 - April 2023

- Worked on different game and app projects based on their research
- Changing learning with gamification by games and apps
- Integrating Google Firebase & GameSparks as the backend for games

### **FRAG Games**, Pakistan — Senior Game Engineer

December 2014 - May 2017

- Coda Quest Educational 3D real-time multiplayer server synced PC game which includes multiple games inside an open world developed using Unity3D and uLink. I implemented a multiplayer Shrine System, Generic Animation System, Battle Animations, Multiple Platform Game along the beanstalk, Optimizations, UI Animations and Integrations. Also, I have done some Editor and Inspector scripting where required.
- Ganja Goons Worked on a 3D Base-Building isometric strategy game in the same vein as Clash of Clans, Boom Beach and Hay Day, with primary work on Isometric Controls, UI integration, Replay, AI, Buildings, Units, Crops, Resources, Achievements, Grid system and Optimizations developed using Unity3D for iPhone, iPad and Android.
- Sorcerer's Ring Complex turn—based 3D mobile game developed using Unity for iPhone and iPad where users have to draw certain gestures on—screen to cast spells. The game includes an immersive single—player campaign. The player plays against an advanced AI. The game also features a levelling system and scripted tutorials that allow players to learn and transition from one level to another—implemented multiplayer Raid Boss module.

## **Sunstar Technology Group LLC,** Pakistan — *Unity Game Developer* (2D & 3D)

July 2014 - November 2014

- Worked on 3D game projects using Unity3D (for Android). One of some individually in-house developed games is:
  - Death Shooter Commando 3D
- Used Mecanim Animation System for animation in games
- Used NGUI Unity plugin to enhance the quality & interaction of games
- Implemented different Ad SDKs (like Admob, StartApp, and AdBuddiz)

### **PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES**

C, C++, C#, Objective C, Java

PHP, ASP.Net, VB.Net, iOS SDK, Android SDK

HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, AJAX, JSON

SQL, MySQL, SQLite, MongoDB

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Unity, Cocos2D, Android Studio, Xcode, Visual Studio, MonoDevelop, SQL Server, Eclipse, Adobe Dreamweaver

Git, GitHub, GitLab, BitBucket

Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop

Mac OS, Windows

### **PERSONALITY SKILLS**

Quick learner, with good debugging, problem-solving and optimising skills

Take issues and complexity as a challenge with a "Can do" attitude

Effective team player with good communication and interpersonal skills

Focused, punctual and hardworking

## **Jolta Technology**, Pakistan — *Unity Game Developer* (3D)

January 2014 - June 2014

- Worked on 3D game projects using Unity3D oT(for iOS & Android). One of some individually in-house developed games is:
  - Fire Fighter Truck 3D
- Used NGUI Unity plugin to enhance the quality & interaction of games
- Implemented different Ad SDKs (like iAd, Admob, LeadBolt, StartApp, ChartBoost, Heyzap) in FREE versions
- Implemented Facebook SDK

## **Jolta Technology**, Pakistan — iOS Game Developer (2D)

July 2013 - December 2013

- Worked on iPhone and iPad games using Cocos2D. Some individually in-house developed games are:
  - Bubble Shoot Deluxe Ads FREE
  - Bubble Shoot Deluxe
- Implemented different Ad SDKs (like iAd, Revmob, AdWhirl, StartApp, ChartBoost) in FREE versions
- Implemented Facebook and Twitter SDKs

## **Jolta Technology**, Pakistan — *iOS Developer*

April 2013 - June 2013

Removed bugs, updated, implemented different Ad SDKs (like iAd, Revmob, LeadBolt, TapForTap) in FREE versions and added In-App purchases in multiple apps

## **Apponative**, Pakistan — Android Developer (Part-time)

November 2013 - December 2013

- Availcheck This lets you schedule with synchronized online data
- PushWizard Android SDK, Push Notification Service
- Recording Project Using RTMP, live video recording

## **Lahore University of Management Sciences,** Pakistan — *Web Developer*

August 2012 - March 2013

Developed and managed all the technical aspects of their Official Website

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Superior University,** Lahore, Pakistan — BS. Computer Science (Hons.)

2008 - 2012

## **Punjab Group of Sciences**, Sialkot, Pakistan — *F.Sc.* (*Pre-Engineering*)

2006 - 2008

#### OTHER CERTIFICATES

Technology
Entrepreneurship (Online venture-lab.org) in Oct-Dec
2012, Stanford University, CA,

A Crash Course on Creativity (Online - venture-lab.org) in Oct-Dec 2012, Stanford University, CA, US

Artificial Intelligence (Online - ai-class.com) in Oct-Dec 2011, Stanford University, CA, US

### **RESEARCH PROJECTS**

Working methodology of Software houses and reasons which lead them to lock

How to launch a new product in the market

Programming practices to follow

### **HOBBIES**

I play mobile and PC games, surf the net for learning and the latest information about technology

### **LANGUAGES**

English, Urdu, Punjabi, Hindi

#### Reference

Will be provided on-demand